VERONIKA YORDANOVA

@ veronika.yordanova.11@gmail.com

4 +44 758 3571 681

♀ London, UK

in www.linkedin.com/in/veronikayordanova

SUMMARY

As a Solutions Architect, I bridge the gap between business needs and technology execution. Coming from a background in robotics and defence, I have experience in delivering complex projects and I understand well the difficulties that arise when developing new technology for legacy systems. I have a PhD in robotics from UCL. This gave me the opportunity to collaborate and engage with multidisciplinary and multicultural teams - I have worked in national and international organisations in the UK, Germany and Italy. As part of my previous role as a NATO scientist, I helped shape the future of maritime autonomous systems. Recently, I have transitioned into consulting and deliver digital transformation solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Solutions Architect

Curvestone

🛗 Jul 2021 - Current

♀ London, UK

- I am a Solutions Architect the bridge between business and technology
- Planning and executing the delivery of solutions, ensuring that cost, quality and time are appropriately balanced
- Working with a range of business stakeholders to understand the needs and outcomes they are seeking and translate these into clearly defined requirements
- Coordinating with multiple teams to form end-to-end solution designs which meet business needs
- Leading the product growth and adoption through a sales and customer success strategy
- Championing projects within new initiatives and market sectors

Scientist

NATO STO Centre for Maritime Research and Experimentation (CMRE)

♀ La Spezia, Italy

- Led full systems development life cycle for R&D defence project
 I coordinated interdisciplinary teams to deliver new data collection approach for autonomous underwater vehicle resulting in 31% efficiency gain and no data quality reduction
- Managed technical conversations and cross-organization communications between developers, operators and management
- Defined project goals in the annual programme of work matching technology developments to long-term customer vision
- Developed and tested at sea algorithms and prototypes for autonomous systems
- Presented work outcomes and interacted with multi-national and diverse audiences: researchers, engineers, national representatives, navy personnel, the wider scientific community

Researcher

Atlas Elektronik GmbH

math Aug 2016 - Jun 2017

- ♥ Bremen, Germany
- Developed innovative research combining company's latest autonomous vehicle product and PhD project
- Led technical conversations with company to align R&D needs and academic demands

EDUCATION

PhD: Robotics

University College London

🛗 Sep 2013 - Feb 2018

MRes: Security and Crime Science

University College London

MSc: Spacecraft Technology and

Satellite Communications

University College London

BEng: Aeronautical Engineering

Technical University Sofia

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Demonstrated maritime autonomous system concept for data collection at NATO exercise (7 Nations and 35 assets present) - led research, integration and at-sea testing
- Organised an international student business plan competition (UCL/LBS CleanTech Challenge) in a team of 10
- Secured multiple scholarships from industry, government and EU (Marie Curie grant) and international placements
- Awarded first prize in poster competition at the 8th International Crime Science Conference in London, UK
- UCL scholarship for course in London Business School (LBS) - Strategic Innovation
- Deep Learning and Reinforcement Learning Summer School, University of Montreal (17% acceptance rate)

SKILLS

Technical: python, Linux, git, Latex **Languages**: English, Bulgarian (basic Russian and Italian)